

Muhammad Sohaib Ashraf

Robotic Software Engineer

Robotics Software Engineer with two years of experience, working at Epazz, Lahore. Masters in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, as well as a bachelor's degree in Software Engineering. Ambitious to prove my worth in the development of advanced robotic technologies. Experienced in developing scripts using ROS, Isaac SDK, Python, C++, Al, and ML algorithms. Additionally, I am a competent developer with expertise in Unity 3D, C#, MATLAB, R, and PHP.

\searrow

suhaib.sabi@hotmail.com



+923475355393



Lake City, Lahore, Pakistan



suhaibashraf.github.io/Portfol io



linkedin.com/in/muhammadsohaib

SKILLS

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Robotics

Computer Vision

ROS, Isaac SDK

C#, C++, Python

Unity3d Engine

QT

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Badminton

Cricket

Video Games

Travelling

Tech News

Learning Languages

WORK EXPERIENCE

Robotic Software Engineer Epazz

03/2021 - Present

Lahore, Pakistan

Tasks

- Defined software requirements and carried out design procedures from scratch.
- Supervising software developers, graphic designers, and other team members.
- Worked jointly with UX designers to design and build user interfaces.
- Choose appropriate libraries and open source technologies for project integration and synchronizing software to new hardware, using innovative technologies.
- Working on multiple robotics and IoT projects using technologies such as Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Neural Networks, ANN, CONV, Tensorflow, QT, ROS, C++, and Python.

Software Engineer (Robotics) Oneberry Technologies

12/2019 - 10/2020

Singapore

Tasks

- Adapted three existing robotics applications to improve performance and introduce various new features
- Semantic segmentation was used to enable the robot to navigate autonomously along a side walk with the additional capability of obstacle avoidance using RGB cameras.
- In a fast-paced environment, I worked on robotics vision and autonomous movement using the Isaac SDK, ROS, Python, C++, and several Slam and vision scripts.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Augmum (03/2021 - Present)

Augmum is a robotics project with a variety of applications. One of the primary goals of this project is to learn any kind of humanoid hand movement and execute it using a robotic arm without human intervention.

Sidewalk Robot (12/2019 - 03/2020)

Developed an application for the Sidewalk Robot Project that uses the Isaac SDK and ROS to deploy the robot on the sidewalk. This robot utilises standard cameras without the use of LiDAR or depth cameras. It performs semantic segmentation on the camera's frames to identify the sidewalk.

EDUCATION

MSc Artificial Intelligence and Robotics University of Hertfordshire/Hatfield, UK

01/2018 - 07/2019

Distinction, 4.5/5.0, 92% in thesis

Courses

- Machine Learning and Neural Networks
- Artificial Life with Robotics

- Theory and Practice of Artificial Intelligence
- Evolutionary Flocking Shooter

BS Software Engineering

University of Management and Technology

02/2013 - 08/2017

Courses

- Object Oriented ProgrammingMobile Application Development
- Computer Vision
- Computer Graphics